Long-form AI videos like these have been
最近，像这样的长篇人工智能视频
popping up lately.
层出不穷。
And I just spent the last few weeks
我花了过去几周的时间才
figuring out the best workflow to get
找到获得这些结果的最佳工作流程
those outputs. And if you've tried this
。 如果你
yourself, you know how difficult it is
自己尝试过，你就会知道，
to create a long AI video without having
要制作一段较长的 AI 视频而不让
your character or location shift. With
角色或地点发生变化是多么困难。
most methods, the longer your video is,
大多数方法都是如此，视频越长，
the more chances there are for
就越容易
consistency to break. But, I figured out
出现不一致的情况。 但是，我找到了在
outputs while keeping everything
保持所有内容完美无缺的同时，获得长时间电影级输出的最佳方法
perfectly intact. So, in this video, I'm
。 所以，在这段视频中，我
going to show you the exact workflow I
将向你展示我
use to create long AI clips all while
用来创建长篇 AI 短片的完整工作流程，同时
keeping all your assets consistent. Most
保持所有素材的一致性。 大多数
people open up their video generator,
人打开视频生成器，
type in a prompt, and just start
输入提示信息，然后就开始
generating. And then they wonder why
生成视频。 然后他们就纳闷了为什么
their clips don't connect, why the
他们的片段无法衔接，为什么
character looks different in every shot,
每个镜头中角色看起来都不一样，
and why the whole thing feels like a
以及为什么整个视频感觉像是
random collection of scenes instead of
随机场景的集合，而不是
an actual video. So, the first thing I
一个真正的视频。 所以，我要做的第一件事
am going to do is open up Claude, paste
就是打开 Claude，粘贴
in this prompt, and get back a full
这个提示，然后获取
scene description for the video we are
我们即将制作的视频的完整场景描述
about to make. And this is actually the
。 而这
step that fixes everything. When you
一步实际上解决了所有问题。 在接触任何生成工具
have a written scene description before
之前，如果已经有了场景的书面描述，那么
asset you create and every clip you
你创建的每个素材和生成的每个片段
generate is pulling in the same
都会朝着同一个
direction. Without it, you are asking
方向发展。 如果没有它，你就是在要求
the AI to make creative decisions for
人工智能为你做出创造性的决定
you, and it is going to make different
，而它每次都会做出不同的
ones every single time. The more detail
决定。
you put into this up front, the easier
你事先准备得越详细，
the prompting process is later, too,
之后的提示过程就越容易，
because you are not inventing the story
因为你不用临时编造故事
on the fly. You are just translating
。 你只是在翻译
something that already exists. Now, we
已经存在的东西。 现在，我们
have our story locked in and every
的故事线已经确定，
decision we make from here is going to
我们接下来做的每一个决定都将围绕这个主题展开
come back to this. But, before we start
。 但是，在我们开始
creating our videos to maximize our
制作视频以最大限度地提高视频
consistency, we need a set of assets.
质量的一致性之前，我们需要一套素材。
The model has no anchor yet. It does not
该模型目前还没有锚点。 它不
know what your character looks like or
知道你的角色长什么样，也不知道
what the environment should feel like.
环境应该是什么感觉。
Every clip is going to be a completely
每一个片段都将是
fresh guess and the results are going to
全新的猜测，结果也会
reflect that. So, instead of jumping
反映这一点。 因此，
straight into video generation, we are
我们不会直接开始视频生成，而是
going to build three assets first and
先构建三个素材，
once those are locked in, every
一旦这些素材确定下来，
generation we run is going to reference
我们运行的每一次生成都会
them directly. This is the part of the
直接引用它们。 这是
workflow that most people skip because
工作流程中大多数人会跳过的部分，因为
it feels like extra steps before the fun
它感觉像是有趣​​部分之前的额外步骤
part. But these three assets are the
。 但正是这三项要素让
entire reason the final video holds
最终的视频
together. The platform I use for all of
浑然一体。 我用来做这一切的平台
this is OpenArt, which is an all-in-one
是 OpenArt，它是一个一体化
tool that gives us access to everything
工具，可以为我们提供
we need to create our video. When you
创建视频所需的一切。
log in, you will land on the main
登录后，您将进入
homepage and you'll see multiple
主页，并看到多个
options: story, video, image, character,
选项：故事、视频、图片、角色、
world, and audio. We are going to be
世界和音频。 我们将在
moving between a few of these to create
这些工具之间切换，以生成
our outputs. The three assets we need
我们的输出结果。
before we touch the video generator are
在开始使用视频生成器之前，我们需要三个素材：
a consistent character, a full-body
一个始终如一的角色、一张该角色的全身
styled image of them, and a location so
造型图片，以及一个拍摄地点，以便
the environment is consistent from shot
场景在各个镜头中保持一致
to shot. Each one solves a different
。 它们各自解决不同的
consistency problem and they work
一致性问题，并
together as a system. If you want to
作为一个系统协同工作。 如果你想
follow along with me, I've left a link
跟着我的步骤操作，我
for OpenArt in the description below.
在下面的描述中留下了 OpenArt 的链接。   我们先从
Let's start with the character. From the
角色说起。 从
main homepage, I'm going to click on
主页上，我将点击
character, then create character. You'll
角色，然后创建角色。 你会
see multiple options pop up and
看到弹出多个选项，
depending on what type of character you
根据你
want to create, each one has a different
想创建的角色类型，每个选项都有不同的
use. If you want to experiment and need
用途。 如果你想进行实验，并且需要
something fast without having anything
快速实现某个功能而又不想使用任何
pre-built, then start with a
预先构建好的功能，那么就从
description. If you want to build a
描述开始。 如果你想创建一个
fully consistent character that's
完全虚构且前后一致的角色
completely made up, the build your
，“创建你的
character option works best. But for
角色”选项是最佳选择。 但是
this, I want the character to look just
，我希望这个角色看起来和
like me, so I'll select start from an
我一模一样，所以我选择从
image and upload a picture of myself. A
图像开始，然后上传一张我自己的照片。
clear front-facing or 3/4 view shot
正面或四分之三侧面的清晰照片
works best because it gives the model
效果最佳，因为它能让模特获得
the most complete information about your
关于你
facial features and proportions. The
面部特征和比例的最完整信息。
more clearly the model can read your
模型越能从参考图像中清晰地读取你的
face from the reference image, the more
面部信息，
accurately it is going to reproduce it
就能
across every generation. I am going to
在每一代中越准确地再现你的面部特征。 我要
upload my image, give the character a
上传我的图片，给角色
name, I am calling her Isa, and hit
起个名字，我叫她伊莎，然后点击
create. The training process only takes
创建。 培训过程只需
a few minutes. Once your character is
几分钟。 角色
saved, she gets her own tag. In our
保存后，她会获得自己的标签。 就我们
case, that is at Isa, and from this
而言，这是在 Isa，从现在
point forward, every single generation
开始，
we run is going to include that tag in
我们运行的每一代都会在提示中包含该标签
the prompt. The saved character tag
。 已保存的角色标签会
locks her face, but it does not lock her
锁定她的脸部，但不会锁定她的
outfit, her hair, or how she is styled
服装、发型或
overall. And this is a gap that catches
整体造型。 而这正是
a lot of people out. The overall look
许多人容易忽略的一个漏洞。 整体画面风格的
shifts in ways that make the video feel
变化让视频感觉
disconnected, even though the face is
不连贯，即使从技术上讲，脸是
technically the same person. The fix is
同一个人。 解决方法是提供
a full-body reference image that defines
一张全身参考图，
exactly how she looks for your specific
精确定义她在你特定
video. This becomes the visual contract
视频中的形象。 这便成为
for the whole project. Every clip we
整个项目的视觉契约。 我们生成的每个片段
generate is going to reference this
都会参考这张
image, so the model knows not just who
图片，所以模特不仅知道
she is, but exactly how she looks in the
自己是谁，还能确切地知道自己在
video we're making. I am going to head
我们制作的视频中的样子。 我要
back to the main homepage and click on
返回主页并点击
image. For the model, I am selecting GPT
图片。 对于模型，我选择 GPT
image two. I will set the aspect ratio
图像二。 我将把宽高比设置
to 16 by 9, paste in the styling prompt,
为 16:9，粘贴样式提示，
make sure I am tagging at Isa, so her
确保我标记了 Isa，这样她的
face carries through into the image, and
脸就会出现在图像中，然后
generate. I'm generating two variations,
生成。 我生成了两个版本，
so we can choose the best option. She
以便我们可以选择最佳方案。 她
still looks exactly like me, but now
看起来仍然和我一模一样，但现在
she's styled in jungle combat gear,
她穿着丛林作战服，这正是
exactly like I asked to match our
我之后要求我们搭配
outfits later. This is the reference
服装的。 这是
every video clip is going to pull from
所有视频片段的参考，
to keep her outfit and overall look
以保持她的服装和整体造型
consistent. Something worth noting here
一致。 值得注意的
is that the 16 by 9 aspect ratio is
是，16:9 的宽高比是
intentional. We want this reference
故意设计的。 我们希望参考
image to be as close as possible to the
图像的格式尽可能接近
format our videos are going to be
我们将要生成的视频格式
generated in. The more the reference
。参考图像与
matches the output format, the more
输出格式的匹配度越高，
cleanly the model translates the visual
模型就能越准确地转换视觉
information across. Staying in the image
信息。 保持相同的模型和宽高比，继续进行图像
generation workflow with the same model
生成工作流程
and aspect ratio, it's time to create
，现在是时候创建
our location. I'll paste in this prompt
我们的地点了。 我将粘贴此提示信息
to generate the jungle temple interior.
以生成丛林神庙内部场景。
The attention to detail makes this look
细节处理得非常到位，看起来就像
like a screenshot from a film. This is
电影截图一样。 这
going to anchor the visual environment
将为
for our clips, and it gives the model a
我们的片段确定视觉环境，并为模型提供一个
concrete reference for what this space
具体的参考，使其了解这个空间的
looks and feels like, rather than
外观和感觉，而不是
leaving it to interpret the description
让模型自己去解读描述
on its own. The reason we generate the
。 我们将
location as a separate asset, rather
位置信息生成为单独的资源，而不是
than just describing it video prompt, is
仅仅在视频提示中描述它，其原因与
the same reason we generate the styled
我们生成样式化
character image. The visual reference
角色图像的原因相同。 视觉参考能够为
gives the model far more specific
模型提供
information than text alone. When you
比单纯文字更具体的信息。 当你
hand it an image, it has a direct visual
给它一张图片时，它就有了直接的视觉
target to work from. Now that we have
目标可以参考。 现在我们已经拥有了
all three of our assets, it's time to
全部三项素材，是时候
create our cinematic videos. But first,
制作我们的电影级视频了。 但首先，
I want to show you something about the
我想向你们展示
video generation step that most people
视频生成步骤中大多数人直到为时已
do not think about until it is too late.
晚才想到的一些事情。
between clips is actually what creates
视频片段之间参考素材的变化方式，实际上创造了
the continuity across the whole video.
整个视频的连贯性。   在
And understanding this before you start
开始制作之前理解这一点，就能
generating is what separates a workflow
区分出能够
that produces a cohesive final video
制作出连贯的最终视频的工作流程和能够
from one that produces three clips that
制作出三个恰好
happen to feature the same character.
包含同一角色的片段的工作流程。
Clip one uses both the styled character
片段一同时使用了样式化的角色
image and the location image as
图像和地点图像作为
references. That establishes the look
参考。 这样就确立了第一代产品的外观
and the environment together in the
和环境
first generation. Clips two and three
。 片段二和片段三
drop the location image and replace it
舍弃了位置图像，并
with the previous video as a reference
用之前的视频作为参考
instead. That is the key move. By
代替。 这是关键一步。 通过将
feeding each new clip the video that
每个新片段播放
came before it, you are telling the
之前的视频，就相当于告诉
model to continue from where the last
模型从上一个
clip ended, rather than starting fresh.
片段结束的地方继续播放，而不是从头开始播放。
The environment carries forward
环境自然而然地延续下去
naturally, the motion flows, and the
，动作流畅自然，
whole thing reads as one continuous
整个画面看起来像是一段连续的
piece of footage, rather than three
影像，而不是三个
separate generations. Back on the main
独立的世代。 回到
home page, I am going to click on video
主页，我将点击视频，
and select SeaDance 2.0 as the model.
然后选择 SeaDance 2.0 作为模型。
This model works specifically well for
这种模型特别适合
this workflow, and it's what allows us
这种工作流程，如果使用得当，它能帮助我们
to create long clips with consistency if
创建出连贯的长片段
used correctly. Most AI video generators
。 大多数AI视频生成器将
cap you at around 5 to 10 seconds per
每个视频片段的时长限制在5到10秒左右
clip. SeeDance 2.0 generates clips up to
。  SeeDance 2.0 可生成
15 seconds long. That is a significant
最长 15 秒的视频片段。 对于长篇叙事内容来说，这是一个显著的
difference for long-form narrative
区别，
content because it means you need fewer
因为这意味着你需要更少的
clips to tell a complete story, and
片段来讲述一个完整的故事，而
fewer clips means fewer consistency gaps
更少的片段意味着需要管理的连贯性差距也更少
to manage. On top of that, SeeDance
。 除此之外，SeeDance
handles multi-shot sequences within a
还能在单代生成过程中处理多镜头序列
single generation along with audio. So,
以及音频。 因此，
instead of generating one camera angle
与其一次生成一个摄像机角度
at a time and hoping it flows into the
并希望它能流畅地过渡到
next, you can describe multiple shots in
下一个角度，不如在一个提示中描述多个镜头，
one prompt and the model executes them
模型会将它们
as one continuous clip with high-quality
作为一个连续的片段执行，并
audio included.
包含高质量的音频。
For our first clip, I am uploading image
在我的第一个视频片段中，我上传了
one styled I saw and image two, the
第一张我看到的图片（风格图）和第二张图片（
jungle temple interior, as my reference
丛林寺庙内部）作为参考
images. Set the model to SeeDance 2.0,
图片。 将模型设置为 SeeDance 2.0，
the duration 15 seconds, write your
持续时间设置为 15 秒，输入
prompt,
提示信息，
and generate.
然后生成。
What comes back is a strong first clip.
返回的是一段精彩的第一段视频。
The character is pushing through the
角色正穿过
jungle toward the temple entrance. The
丛林，向寺庙入口前进。
lighting is exactly what we described in
灯光效果与我们在场景中描述的完全一致
the scene, and the multi-shot structure
，多镜头拍摄结构也
is working. We are getting multiple
奏效了。 在短短 15 秒内，我们就能看到多个
beats of action within one 15-second
动作瞬间
generation. That is the foundation the
。
next two clips are going to build on.
接下来的两个视频片段将以此为基础展开。
One thing I want you to notice is how
我想让你们注意一点，那就是
the reference images are doing their job
参考图片在这里是如何发挥作用的
here. The outfit and the location are
。 服装和拍摄地点都和
exactly like our reference images. For
我们的参考图片完全一致。 对于
the second clip, instead of uploading
第二个片段，
the location image again, I am going to
我不会再次上传位置图像，而是
click the upload button inside SeeDance
点击 SeeDance 2.0 内的上传按钮，
2.0 and select video one as the video
并选择视频一作为视频
reference. This tells the model to
参考。 这告诉模型
continue from where the last clip ended.
从上一个片段结束的地方继续播放。
I am still keeping image one as a
我仍然保留第一张图作为
character reference. So, her look stays
人物参考图。 所以，她的外形保持
locked, but the environment and the
不变，但环境和
motion now flow directly from the
动作现在直接沿用
previous generation rather than being
上一代的设计，而不是从头开始
reestablished from scratch. I'll paste
重新设计。 我会把
in this prompt.
这段提示粘贴进来。
And you can see exactly how that
您可以清楚地看到这种
continuity works. She still looks
连续性是如何运作的。 她看起来依然
consistent, but she's now moving through
很正常，但她现在正在
the corridor and the whole clip feels
走廊里走动，整个片段感觉
like a natural continuation of the
像是故事的自然延续
story. We are getting five different
。 在同一代人的时间里，我们看到了五种不同的
shots and a clear narrative progression
镜头和一个清晰的叙事发展
all within one generation. If we were
。 如果我们
working with a 5-second model, we would
采用 5 秒模型，
need three or four clips just to cover
仅此部分就需要三到四个片段，
this section and every one of those
而每一次
transitions would be a new consistency
过渡都会带来新的连贯性
risk. It's the same process for the
风险。
third clip, but now I am uploading the
第三个视频片段的处理过程相同，但这次我上传的是
previous video and keeping image one as
之前的视频，并将第一张图片作为
the character reference. I'll generate
角色参考图。 我将
with this prompt.
根据这个提示生成。
This is the moment everything has been
一切都是为了这一刻而
building towards. SeaDance can keep up
铺垫的。  SeaDance 能够跟上
with the intense action of the scene
场景中激烈的动作，
with only minor flaws. But honestly,
只有一些小瑕疵。 但说实话，
considering how much it's handling all
考虑到它同时要处理这么多数据
at once, there's simply no other model
，目前根本没有其他车型
right now that could keep up. The
能够与之匹敌。
character is consistent across all three
三个片段中人物性格保持一致
clips. The environment escalates the way
。 环境按照故事需要逐步升级
the story called for, moving from the
，从
jungle entrance to the corridor to the
丛林入口到走廊再到
inner sanctum in a way that feels like a
内部圣所，这种转变让人感觉像是
real progression. And the audio across
真正的进步。 这
all three clips is building the way a
三个片段的音效都以一种
proper action sequence should.
恰当的动作序列应有的方式层层递进。
Now that we have all our clips, it's
现在我们已经收集齐了所有片段，是
time to put them all together for our
时候将它们组合起来，制作
final long-form AI video. I am using
最终的长篇人工智能视频了。 我用的是
CapCut for this, but any editor works. I
CapCut，但任何编辑器都可以。 我
am going to import all three clips and
打算导入这三个视频片段，并按
arrange them in order. Once the clips
顺序排列。 等视频片段
are in order, I am going to pull in a
整理好之后，我会配上一段
music track to sit underneath the whole
音乐作为整个视频的背景音乐
thing. The audio we generated with each
。 我们为每个片段生成的音频
clip handles the in-scene sounds, but
处理场景内的声音，但
the audio track is what ties all three
音轨将所有三个
clips together into one continuous audio
片段连接在一起，形成一个连续的音频
experience. Now, let's look at our final
体验。 现在，让我们来看最后一个
video.
视频。
This looks really good. It's almost a
看起来真不错。 它时长将近一
minute long with a full narrative while
分钟，叙事完整，同时
still maintaining consistency across all
所有素材都保持一致
the assets. With this workflow, you can
。 通过这种工作流程，您可以
create long AI videos without having
创建较长的 AI 视频，而无需在每次
change scenes. And with OpenArt, you get
切换场景时都让角色发生变化。 通过 OpenArt，您
access to everything you need under a
只需
single subscription. So, if you want to
订阅一次即可获得所需的一切。 所以，如果您想
create your own long-form AI videos,
创建自己的长篇人工智能视频，
click the link in the description to
请点击说明中的链接
sign up to OpenArt. Thanks for watching
注册 OpenArt。 感谢收看，我们下期
and I'll see you in the next one.
再见。